Guide to the Nathaniel Tarn Papers, ca. 1939-2000 M1132
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Literary Correspondence
  - Subseries Q-6. Other Publishers' Files and Literary Materials: Posters and Oversized Artwork
    - Canterbury Tales [color poster, Bob Masse, 1967, 58cm x 37cm] (Box 1000, Folder 29)
    - Bob Northcutt [color poster, Bob Masse, n.d., 59cm x 39cm] (Box 1000, Folder 30)
    - Congreso Cultural de la Habana [poster, 1/11/68, 100cm x 32cm] (Box 1000, Folder 31)
    - Untitled portrait [Mendelson, 1956, 58cm x 45cm] (Box 1000, Folder 32)
    - Untitled art, graphite on paper, 1956; ballet costume designs on back, 1948 [Nathaniel Tarn, 1954, 77cm x 56cm] (Box 1000, Folder 33)
    - Che Guevera [Black and white photograph reproduction, poster, n.d., 85cm x 66cm] (Box 1000, Folder 1)
    - Hasta la victoria siempre [Color poster, n.d., 75cm x 46cm] (Box 1000, Folder 2)
    - Salon de Mayo, 29 de Julio, 9th aniversario [Color poster, n.d., 75cm x 46cm] (Box 1000, Folder 3)
    - Cien anos de lucha 1868-1968 [Color poster, 1968, 60cm x 33cm] (Box 1000, Folder 4)
    - Vietnam vencera, Vietnam will win, Vietnam vaincra...: Tricontinental Committee of Support to Vietnam December 20 [Color poster, no year, 55cm x 33cm] (Box 1000, Folder 5)
    - Cleaver for President: Black Panther Party, Peace and Freedom Party [Black and white poster, Jamerson Printing, circa 1968, 56cm x 44cm] (Box 1000, Folder 6)
    - I shall vote labor: Christopher Logue, Turret Books/Goliard Press publishing announcement [Color poster, no. 100/1000, March, 1966, 56cm x 44cm] (Box 1000, Folder 7)
    - Live five [Color poster, Bob Masse, 1967, 56cm x 33cm] (Box 1000, Folder 8)
    - Love [Color poster, Bob Masse, 1967, 59cm x 43cm] (Box 1000, Folder 9)
    - Fisherwoman [Color poster, Bob Masse, 1967, 60cm x 37cm] (Box 1000, Folder 10)
    - Musrum: Eric Thacker and Anthony Earnshaw, Jonathan Cape publishing announcement [Black and white poster, October 24, ?, 77cm x 49cm] (Box 1000, Folder 11)
    - Beeton's Book of Household Management, Jonathan Cape publishing announcement [color poster, n.d., 73cm x 36cm] (Box 1000, Folder 12)
    - Transatlantic Review, Issue 16 [Magazine publishing announcenment, black and poster, n.d., 45cm x 57cm] (Box 1000, Folder 13)
    - My White Bicycle, by Tomorrow [Color poster, n.d., 75cm x 50cm] (Box 1000, Folder 14)
    - UFO Coming [Color concert poster, Osiris Age[n?] 1967, 75cm x 50cm] (Box 1000, Folder 15)
    - Alfred Stockham: Paintings, Drawings, Prints [NYC Art Gallery show announcement color poster 6/29/68, 75cm x 50cm] (Box 1000, Folder 16)
- Series 3. Anthropology and General Scholarship
  Series III holds not only correspondence files from Tarn's academic and professional career as an anthropologist (under the name Edward Michael Mendelson), but also the research notes and materials from his field work in Guatemala and Burma. Among the anthropological correspondents are found: Isaac Chiva, Stanley Diamond, Fred Eggan, Sir Raymond Firth, Sir Edmund Leach, Claude Levi-Strauss, Margaret Mead, Robert Redfield, and nearly two hundred others. In addition, correspondence and material relating to Tarn's academic and professional transition from anthropology to comparative literature, his strong interest in Buddhism, lecture notes from his own undergraduate and graduate training, and later course material from teaching assignments at Rutgers University during the 1970s-1980s, are found in this series.
  - Subseries R. U.S. Anthropologists Individual and Group Correspondence Files
    - Carson, W. (Philippines, Middle East, US Govt. fellow student of NT) (Box 85, Folder 1)
      14 als, 13 tls, 26 pages, 1957-64.
    - Diamond, Stanley (Africa, General Theory, Poetry & Anthropology, The New School): (Box 85, Folder 2)
      13 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 14 pages & approx.40 pp. of varied copy re SD and poetry, 1980-+91.
    - Eggan, Fred (N.America, Phillippines, Kinship Theory, U Chicago, Teacher of NT): (Box 85, Folder 3)
      4 als; 8 pages & letterpress Memorial Program, 1980-+85.
    - Friedrich, Paul (Indo-European, Anthropology & Poetry, U Chicago): (Box 85, Folder 4)
      13 tls; 14 pages & copy, 1979-83.
    - Leslie, Charles (Mexico, India, Medical Anthropology, NYU, U Delaware, Fellow Student of NT) (Box 85, Folder 5)
      13 als; 42 tls, 12 handwritten postcards, 2 typed postcards; 66 pages, 1957-
    - Leslie, Charles (Box 85, Folder 6)
      [Copies of email, 1 handwritten postcard, 1 tls, 1997-2000; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
    - Nash, Manning (Maya, Burma, U Chicago, Fellow Student of NT) (Box 85, Folder 7)
      4 tls; 4 pages, 1954-67.
    - Redfield, Robert (Yucatan, General Theory, U Chicago, Teacher of NT) (Box 85, Folder 8)
      2 als, 42 tls; 1 telegram; 59 pages record of NT fieldwork and Ph.D., 1 tls from Margaret Redfield, 1953-+1956
    - Silverman, Sydel, and Wolf, Eric (Box 85, Folder 9)
      [Correspondence regarding Reconsidering the Ancients lecture series, 1975-1980; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Miscellaneous Group Files 1960s-1970s (Box 85, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with: Arizpe, Lourdes (Mexico, UNAM); Crapanzano, Victor; Davis, Sandy; Fagan, Brian M. (Africa, UCSB); Feldman, Lawrence H.; Harnad, Stevan; Myerhoff, Barbara (Yaqui, UCLA); Metzger, Deena; Nash, June (Latin America, CUNY); Peacock, James L; Pfeiffer, John; Ramanujan, Attipat Krishnaswami; Singer, Milton (India, U. Chicago); Spiro, Melford (Israel, Burma, Psychology, UCSD); Stocking, George (History of A., U. Chicago); Tiger, Lionel (Theory, Rutgers U.) [Names followed by parenthetical information originally listed by Tarn; others found in folder but not listed; names listed by Tarn but not found in this folder: Bascom, William (Cuba, Yoruba Africa, Northwestern); Freidrich, Paul (Indo-European, Poetry, U.Chicago); Lomax, Alan (Musicology, Columbia U.); Silverman, Sydel (Theory, CUNY); Wolf, Eric (Theory, Peasant Societies, CUNY)]
    - Miscellaneous Group Files 1980s-1990s (Box 85, Folder 11)
      Correspondence with: Basso, Ellen; Benedict, Burton (Indian Ocean, U Cal. Berk.); Coggins, [?]; Clifford, James (Theory, UCSB); Fernandez, James (Theory, Princeton); Powers, William; Prattis, Iain (Poetry & A., Carlton U.); Turner, Victor (Theory, U.Virginia); Wilk, Rick (Belize) [Names followed by parenthetical information originally listed by Tarn; others found in folder but not listed; names listed by Tarn but not found in this folder: Bascom, William (Cuba, Yoruba Africa, Northwestern); Freidrich, Paul (Indo-European, Poetry, U.Chicago); Lomax, Alan (Musicology, Columbia U.); Silverman, Sydel (Theory, CUNY); Wolf, Eric (Theory, Peasant Societies, CUNY)]
    - General anthropology (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Subseries S. British Anthropologists Individual Correspondence Files
    - Conze, Edward (Box 85, Folder 13)
      [Correspondence; not originally listed by Tarn}
    - Firth, Sir Raymond (Oceania, Theory, London School of Economics, NT's teacher & chief there) (Box 85, Folder 14)
      2 als, 4 tls, 1 handwritten postcard; 6 pages, 1954-78.
    - Fox, Robin (Theory) (Box 85, Folder 15)
      4 als, 1 tls, 5 handwritten postcards; 6 pages and copy relating to Fox's poetic interests, 1971-88; [photograph].
    - Garrigue, Philippe (Theory, U. Montreal, fellow student of NT) (Box 85, Folder 16)
      15 als, 2 tls; 29 pages, 1954-57
    - Leach, Sir Edmund (Theory, Burma, Cambridge U. eventually Provost, NT's College) (Box 85, Folder 17)
      9 tls; 11 pages, 1966-75.
    - London School of Economics (1953-1957) (Box 86, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with: Forde, Daryll (Africa, University College); Fortes, Meyer (Africa, Theory, Cambridge U); Gluckmann, Max (Africa, Theory; U Manchester); others.
    - Group files (Box 86, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with: Freedman, Maurice (Chinese in S.E. Asia, LSE); Lienhardt, Godfrey (Theory, Africa,Oxford U.); Madge, Charles (sociology, poet, U. Birmingham); Morris, Stephen (S.E.Asia, LSE); others.
    - SOAS [School of Oriental and African Studies] files (1959-1965): [1 of 2] (Box 86, Folder 3)
      Includes general correspondence for 7 years teaching & research at SOAS, SOAS faculty papers and international correspondence[correspondence with: Allott, Anna; Basham, A.L.; Bailey, Fred; Belche{t?]z, Rosemary; Blackmore, H.; Chavarria-Aguilar, O.L.; Crane, Robert; de Bie, Pierre; Dore, R.; Fejos, Paul; Firth, Sir Raymond; Furer-Haimendorf, Von, Christoph; Gatehouse, M.; Heine-Geldern, R.; Henderson, E.J.A.; Henderson, James; Kyung-Bo, SEO; Lang, D.M.; Leslie, Charles; Marsh, Margaret; Mitchell, T.F.; Moyse-Bartlett, H.; Musoke, S.B.K.; Oliver, Joan; Pack, Richard L.; Pavey[sp?], Roger; Phillips, C.A.; Pilgrim, John; Scott, N.C.; Segal, J.B.; Singer, Milton; Stern, Geoffrey; Tax, Sol; Weir, D.H.; Wooding, Kathleen; Wooley, Jeffrey; Yudkin, Judith; and others]
    - SOAS [School of Oriental and African Studies] files (1959-1965): [2 of 2] (Box 86, Folder 4)
      Includes general correspondence for 7 years teaching & research at SOAS, SOAS faculty papers and international correspondence[correspondence with: Amyot, J.; Armitage, Peter; Bivar, A.D.H.; Cowan, C.D.; Gatehouse, M.; Lloyd, P.C.; Lewis, I.M.; MacLean, Colin (The Times); Moyse-Bartlett, H.; O'Leary, Peter; Pearson, J.D.; Reynolds, Chris; Simmons, E.H.S.]
  - Subseries V. Burma Files
    - Preparation and alternatives (ca 1957) (Box 87, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with: Barnes, J.A. (Australian National U, Theory): 1 tls 1 page; Fitzgerald, C.P. (Australian National U, China History): 1 tls, 1 page; Christie, A.H. (SOAS, S.E.Asia History): 1 als, 1 page; Lobsinger-Dellenbach, M. (Ethnog. Museum, Geneva, Tibet): 2 tls, 2 pages; Mead, Margaret (American Mus Natural History; Theory, Oceania): 1 als, 3 tls, 4 pages; Metraux, A. (UNESCO, Carribean): 2 tls, 2 pages; Palmier, L. (Indonesia): 4 tls, 4 pages; Rosser, Colin (SOAS, India): 1 als, 1 page; Singer, Milton (U Chicago, India) 1 tls, 1 page; [and others]
    - U.K. files (1958 - early 60s) (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with: Allen, G.F. (UK Ambassador, SOAS, Burmese): 1 als, 1 page; Allott, Anna (SOAS, Burmese): 3 als, 3 pages; Collis, Maurice (India Civil Service, Burma): 1 als, 4 tls; 4 pages; Firth, Sir Raymond (LSE, Theory): 1 tls, 1 page; Forge, Anthony (Australian Nat. U. New Guinea): 4 tls, 4 pages; Harvey, G.E. (ICS, Burma History): 2 als 2 pages; Horner, I.B (Pali Text Society): 1 als, 1 tls, 2 pages; Humphreys, Christopher (King's Councillor; Buddhism): 1 tls 1 page; Hurwitz, J. (Sociology Institute, the Hague): 1 als 1 page; Laffont, R. (EFEO, Laos): 1 tls, 1 page; Luce, Gordon (Bloomsbury Group; Burma Archeology): 1 als, 1 page & copy; Sarkisyanz, Emmanuel (Freiburg U, S.E.Asia): 3 als, 2 tls, 5 pages; Werblowsky, R.Z. (U Jerusalem): 1 als, 1 page; [and others]
    - U.S. Files (1958- late 60s) (Box 87, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with: Brohm, John (AID, Burma): 1 tls, 1 page; Eberhard, W. (U. California, Berk., China History): 6 tls 6 pages; Gard, Richard (Yale, Burma): 3 tls, 3 pages; Geertz, Clifford (U California, later Institute Princeton, Bali, Theory): 1 tls, 1 page; Harper, E.: (Bryn Mawr, Burma): 1 als, 1 page; Jacobson, N. (Winthrop, Burma): 1 tls, 1 page; Lehmann, F.K. (U Illinois, Burma): 2 tls, 2 pages; Mehden, F. Von Der (U Wisconsin, S.E.Asia): 1 tls, 1 page; Moerman, M. (Yale, Thailand): 1 tls, 1 page; Pye, Lucian (MIT, S.E.Asia Political Science): 3 tls, 3 pages; Spiro, Mel: (U.Washington, UCSD; Burma): 1 tls, 1 page; Sturtevant, W. (Smithsonian, Burma): 1 tls, 1 page [not found in this folder]; Textor, R. (Cornell, S.E.Asia, Japan): 2 tls, 2 pages [not found in this folder]; Trager, F. (Council Foreign Relations, S.E.Asia Pol. Sci.): 2 als, 4 tls; 6 pages [not found in this folder]; Thompson, J. (Thai Silk Co.): 1 als, 1 page [not found in this folder]; [and others]
    - Asia Foundation correspondence (1950s-1960s) (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Return From Burma Files (1950s - 1960s) (Box 87, Folder 8)
      [Mostly correspondence, some handdrawn diagrams, brochures]
    - Maurice, David: (Burma, Burma Govt.) (Box 88, Folder 1)
      Extensive correspondence
    - SOAS Afrasian Files (Box 88, Folder 2)
      Texts connected with special issue of SOAS student magazine, on Ethnic Literatures edited by NT, [includes translations by Tarn and]: Tanar Baybars; Anthony Kerrigan; Bernard Lewis; W.S. Merwin; Omar Pound; Amelie Rorty; Dennis Silk; Ruth Fainlight Sillitoe; Alastair Reid; Assia Wevill[Anastassia Gutmann]
    - Burma stuff, sales, 1985-1986 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      [Correspondence regarding sale of Burma material left with SOAS; not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Subseries Y.Miscellaneous Lecture Notes and Materials
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago, 1947-1950s [1 of 2] (Box 123, Folder 1)
        [Ms, ts, mimeographed, carbon copied notes]
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago, 1947-1950s [1 of 2] (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago and Harvard, 1950s [1 of 4] (Box 123, Folder 3)
        [Mostly mimeographed handouts, some ms]
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago and Harvard, 1950s [2 of 4] (Box 123, Folder 4)
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago and Harvard, 1950s [3 of 4] (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - Lecture notes: University of Chicago and Harvard, 1950s [4 of 4] (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - University of Chicago Department of Anthropology handbook for students entering the M.A. program, 1951-1952 (Box 123, Folder 7)
        [Mimeograph copy, ms notes, etc]
      - Classnotes from seminar on current anthropological problems, London School of Economics, 1953-1954 (Box 124, Folder 1)
        [Ms, mimeographed lecture notes]
      - Lecture notes: Comparative literature, Rutgers, 1970-1971 (Box 124, Folder 2)
        [Ms, ts, mimeographed lecture notes]
      - Lecture notes: Heraldry, 1970s, Rutgers[?] [1 of 2] (Box 124, Folder 3)
        [Ms and ts notes, course syllabi, some journal article reprints]
      - Lecture notes: Heraldry, 1970s, Rutgers[?] [2 of 2] (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - Lecture notes: Heraldry 2/Thematics [?] Rutgers, 1975-1976 (Box 124, Folder 5)
        [Mostly ms, some ts notes, some correspondence from students, some journal article reprints]
      - Lecture notes: Surrealism, [Rutgers, 1970s?][1 of 2] (Box 124, Folder 6)
        [Mostly ms, some ts notes]
      - Lecture notes: Modern poetry, [Rutgers, 1970s?][2 of 2] (Box 124, Folder 7)
        [Mostly photocopies of poetry and prose from anthologies, etc.]
      - Lecture notes: Unidentified course, possibly comparative literature, or, survey of world literature (Box 124, Folder 8)
        [Ms notes]
      - Lecture notes: World mythology, Fall, 1984 [Rutgers] (Box 125, Folder 1)
        [Ms and ts notes, course material]
      - Lecture notes: Several courses in literature and poetry, Rutgers, early 1980s (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - Lecture notes: Contemporary literary theory, Rutgers, early 1980s (Box 125, Folder 3)
      - Lecture notes: Structuralism [no date] (Box 125, Folder 4)
        [Ts and ms notes, course material]
      - Alaska 1977: Lecture notes from educational cruise (Box 125, Folder 5)
        [Ts and ms notes, daily programs, some correspondence]
      - Student papers to be kept by Tarn (Box 125, Folder 6)
        [Photocopies and printouts of student papers, some correspondence regarding departmental affairs, Rutgers, early 1980s]
    - Subseries W-1. General Correspondence Files: Anthropology Years
      - Clifton College, Bristol, file, 1940s (Box 88, Folder 4)
        [Hardbound notebook containing handwritten notes on the history of Rome]
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1965 [1 of 2] (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1965 [2 of 2] (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Cambridge (Box 89, Folder 6)
        [Graduation program, final examination booklets, other material]
      - Cambridge lecture notes (Box 89, Folder 7)
        [Handwritten notes on binder paper, subject: political thought]
      - Cambridge notebooks, 1946-1948 (Box 90, Folder 1)
        [Binder contains handwritten notes, subject: survey of literature]
      - Paris (1949-1950) (Box 90, Folder 2)
        [Typed and handwritten notes, subject: anthropology]
      - Lecture and reading notes, Levi-Strauss, Paul Levy, etc., Paris, 1949-1950 (Box 90, Folder 3)
        [Typed and handwritten notes, hand-drawn diagrams, etc., subject: anthropology]
      - Musee de l'Homme Bulletins, January 1951, June 1951, July, 1952 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Musee de l'Homme notebooks, 1949-1952 (Box 90, Folder 5)
        [Handwritten notes, hand-drawn diagrams, etc., subjects: asiethnographie, oceanethno.]
      - Smith-Mundt-Fulbright Scholarship File (1951-3) (Box 90, Folder 6)
        [Correspondence, memorandums, ts of Tarn's Critical notes on some compared and contrasted elements in the development of American and French ethnological theory]
      - Yale foreign students program (Box 91, Folder 1)
        [Pamphlets, brochures, other ephemera, ts of evaluation form]
      - University of Chicago, 1951-1953 [1 of 2] (Box 91, Folder 2)
        [Class notes, ts and copies of several papers by Tarn, newsletters, correspondence, etc.]
      - University of Chicago, 1951-1953 [2 of 2] (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Papers for London School of Economics (Box 91, Folder 4)
        [Copies and ts of several pre-doctorate papers]
      - Academic degrees file, 1948 [1 of 3] (Box 91, Folder 5)
        [Grade school and college prepatory report cards; photocopies of King's College Cambridge diploma and other material; graduate school material; 1937-1965]
      - Academic degrees file, 1948 [2 of 3] (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - Academic degrees file, 1948 [3 of 3] (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - World Fellowship of Buddhists, Bangkok Conference Research File: 1958-59 [1 of 2] (Box 92, Folder 2)
        [Correspondence, copies of reports, brochures, other conference material]
      - World Fellowship of Buddhists, Bangkok Conference Research File: 1958-59 [2 of 2] (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - SOAS: Teaching, lectures (Box 92, Folder 4)
        [Handwritten and typed notes, hand-drawn diagrams]
      - SOAS: Teaching, syllabus (Box 92, Folder 5)
        [Course outlines and other material]
      - SOAS: Teaching, documents (Box 92, Folder 6)
        [Staff circulars, newsletters of the Association of Social Anthropologists, other material]
      - Hawaii-Japan File: 1961 [1 of 2] (Box 93, Folder 1)
        [Mostly correspondence relating to the 10th Pacific Science Congress, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1961, and Tarn's following visit to Japan]
      - Hawaii-Japan File: 1961 [2 of 2] (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Beginnings of "Cultural Survival" Organization File (Box 93, Folder 3)
        [Material from the Society for Protection of Primitive Peoples and establishment of a similarly-named fund, 1969]
      - International History of Religions Association File [1 of 2] (Box 93, Folder 4)
        [Correspondence, newsletters and programs, 1954-late 1960s]
      - International History of Religions Association File [2 of 2] (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Cornell Visiting Professorship Abandonment File, 1967-69 (Box 93, Folder 6)
        [Correspondence, 1966-1967]
      - Passport Files (Box 93, Folder 7)
        [British and French passports, 1950s, 1960s]
      - Immigration to U.S. File, 1969-70 (Box 94, Folder 1)
        [Correspondence, copies of visa application forms, etc.]
  - Subseries U. Guatemalan Maya Files Group Miscellaneous Files
    - Group miscellaneous files (Box 86, Folder 12)
      Alcina, Jose [not originally listed by Tarn]; Arriola, Jorge Luis (IIN Guatemala): 8 tls, 8 pages, 1958-60; Bascom, William (Northwestern U., Yoruba, Afro-American, Cuba): 1 tls, 1 page, 1956; Blom, Franz (Chiapas Maya): 1 tls, 3 typed postcards, 1 page, 1957; Caso, Alfonso (INI, Mexico): 2 tls, 2 pages, 1956; Cerezo, Hugo (IIN, Guatemala): 1 tls; 1 page, 1954; Crevenna, Theo R. [not originally listed by Tarn]; Crocker, Frederick Pat [not originally listed by Tarn]; Davalo Hurtado, E. (SMA, Mexico); 2 tls 2 page, 1956; de Dios Rosales, Juan: (IIN, Guatemala): 4 tls 4 pages, 1950s; Dreyfus-Roche, Simone (Paris): 2 tls; 2 pages, 1953;Firth, J.R. (Linguistics, SOAS): 1 tls; 1 Page, 1953; [not found in this folder]; Foster, George M. (Smithsonian, Mexico): 2 tls; 2 pages, 1952; Hirshberg, Dick {not originally listed by Tarn]; Jeffries, E.W. [not originally listed by Tarn]; McQuown, Norman (U. Chicago, Maya Linguistics): 2 tls; 2 pages; 195; Mendoza, Alicia [not originally listed by Tarn]; Noval, Joaquin (IIN, Guatema): 3 tls; 3 pages, 1954; O'Gorman, Edmundo (History & Philosophy, Colegio de Mexico): 1 als; 2 pages, 1951; Singer, Milton [not originally listed by Tarn]; Thompson, Sir J. Eric (Maya): correspondence [not found in this folder]; Wauchope, Robert (Tulane U., Maya): 6 tls; 7 pages; Ziegler, Dewey K. [not originally listed by Tarn]
    - Ph.D Correspondence files (1950s) (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Eggan, Fred (U Chicago; Theory, Teacher of NT): 3 als 6 pages, 1956 - +; Firth, Sir Raymond (LSE, Theory, Teacher of NT): 2 als; 4 pages, 1956; Tax, Sol: (N. America, Theory, U Chicago): 5 tls, 6 pages & memos, 1954-56; Turabian, Kate L. [not originally listed by Tarn]; Wach, Joachim (U Chicago; Hist. of Religion; Ph. D. Sub-Director): 5 als, 5 pages, 1954.
    - Recent Maya files (1970s to present) (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with: Didier Borremans (U del Valle, Guatemala); David Carrasco (U. Colorado, Princeton U); Gary Gossen (SUNY Albany); Norman Hammond (Boston U); Timothy Knab (U de las Americas, Puebla); Christopher Lutz (Mesoamerica); Merle Greene Robertson (PARI, Middle American Art Research Institute); Christopher Wilcox (U Michigan); Jown Wantanabe (Dartmouth C); Sister Alice Zachmann (Guatemalan Human Rights Commission, US), etc. [also: ts of Thirty years later: the Estados Unidos goes to the Moon (Tarn and Martin Prechtel), photocopies of newspaper and magazine articles, brochures, newsletters, invitations to symposiums and conferences, course syllabi, etc.]
    - Guatemala: Miscellaneous Correspondence and Ephemera 1979,1980 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Subseries W-2. General Correspondence Files: Transfer to Comparative Literature Files
    - University of Essex Files (Donald Davie correspondence), 1966. (Box 94, Folder 2)
      [Correspondence, photocopies of newspaper clippings]
    - SUNY Buffalo Summer File, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 3)
      [Correspondence, course outlines, other material]
    - Princeton University Files, 1970-71 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - SUNY Purchase File, 1970 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Rutgers University Files,1970-1972 [1 of 2] (Box 94, Folder 6)
      [Correspondence (some relating to chairmanship nomination), department memoranda, course syllabi, etc.]
    - Rutgers University Files,1970-1972 [2 of 2] (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Rutgers University Files,1973-1976 (Box 94, Folder 8)
      [Mostly correspondence, department memoranda, course syllabi, etc.]
    - Rutgers University Files,1977-1979 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Rutgers University Files,1977-1981 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      [Correspondence, mostly concerning research grants, leaves of absence, sabbaticals]
    - Rutgers University Files,1980-1983 (Box 95, Folder 3)
      [Mostly correspondence, some university memoranda]
    - Rutgers University Files,1982-1984 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Rutgers status battles, 1980 [1 of 2] (Box 95, Folder 5)